太好了
Yes.
你“死”了
You failed.
我没有
I didn't.
枪在我手里
The gun is in my hand.
我还以为我拿到了
I thought I had it.
抱歉 父亲 我下次一定可以的
Sorry, Father. I'll make it next time.
千万不要认为你拥有的一切是理所当然的
Never take anything for granted.
否则上帝会夺走你所拥有的
God will take it from you.
上帝是坏蛋吗
Is God bad?
上帝很公平
God is fair.
你差点就抓到我了 对吗 小家伙
You almost got me, didn't you, boy?
我的白发是从你那里遗传来的吗
Did I get my white hair from you
还是从妈妈那里
or from Mom?
你妈妈遗传给你的
From your mother.
真不敢相信我们连她的照片都没有
I can't believe we don't have any pictures of her.
照片什么的都在大火中被烧毁了
Everything was destroyed in the fire.
你知道的
You know that.
我当时只能救出你
I could only save you.
她漂亮吗
Was she beautiful?
她很聪明
She was smart.
就像你一样
Like you.
我做对了多少
How many did I get?
全对了
All of them.
那我今天可以进城了 对吧
So I get to go to town today, right?
实战中你输了
You failed survival.
已经三个月了
It's been three months.
况且 我刚刚还给你剪了一个很棒的发型
Plus, I just gave you a killer haircut.
请相信我
Trust me.
你必须先通过所有的测试才行
You need to pass all your tests first.
好的 除了些常见的
All right, apart from the usual,
我还订购了五种蕨类植物
I have an order of five ferns,
两种榕属植物
two ficuses,
还有大圆柱藻
and the Columnea grandiosa.
格洛里奥萨
Gloriosa.
我今天能带小凤去吗
Am I taking Phoenix today?
今天不行
Not today.
已经有一段时间没去了
It's been a while.
我说了 不行
I said, no.
你对她管的越严
You either loosen up that leash,
越容易适得其反
or sooner or later, she's gonna bite it off.
跟赫尔南德斯一起去吧
Go with Hernandez.
记得日落前回来
Back by sunset!
好的
I will.
嘿 赫尔南德斯
Hey, Hernandez.
嘿 小美女
Hey, gorgeous.
♪ Fly, bird ♪
♪ All across the mighty sea ♪
♪ Sing, girl ♪
♪ Sing your little heart out For me ♪
真好听
That's beautiful.
这是你自己编的曲子吗
You made that up?
这是我小的时候妈妈唱给我听的
I think my mom sang it to me when I was little.
我只记得前面部分
That first part's all I remember.
你想去祭拜一下她吗
You wanna pay her a visit?
-但是我父亲不想让我去 -只要你不说 我绝对不会说的
But my father doesn't want me--I won't tell if you don't.
♪ Fly, bird ♪
警方已对托马斯·汉尼曼博士发出全州警报
REPORTER Police have issued a statewide alert for Dr. Thomas Hanniman,
此人在底特律地区
who's believed to be running an organ trafficking ring
- 组织经营器官贩运 -谢谢
in the Detroit area.Thank you.
其绑架数量惊人
The alarming number of abductions
且数量近期在该市更是有所上升
has recently risen in the city.
更多消息静待通报 我们会即时向您通报最新情况
This is a developing story. We'll update you
将更多信息公之于众
as more information comes to light.
现在我们来看周末的天气预报
Now let's take a look at the weekend forecast.
大家早上好 我是气象学家杰瑞
JERRY Good morning, everyone. I'm meteorologist Jerry...
谁来帮个忙
Everyone, pull. Help me.
这儿卡住了
It's stuck.
嘿 要试点好玩的吗
Hey, wanna try something?
好吧
Okay.
来吧
Do it.
再快点 再快点
Faster, faster.
我有点晕了
I'm getting dizzy.
嘿 伙计们 进来吃饭了
Hey, guys. Come on in. Dinner.
我不想进去
But I don't wanna go inside.
来吧 伙计们
Come on, guys!
“圣约人庇护所”
"Covenant Shelter."
我跑的比你快
Race you.
嘿 等等
Hey, wait up!
-玩得开心吗 -嗯嗯
You having fun?Mm-hm.
好了 我们走吧
All right, let's go.
我想去小便
I need to pee.
好的 那就快点
Okay, well, be quick.
我可不敢惹毛你父亲
I don't wanna anger your father.
♪ Fly, bird ♪
♪ All across the mighty sea ♪
♪ Sing, girl ♪
♪ Sing your little heart out For me ♪
哇 你真漂亮
Wow, you're pretty.
你叫什么名字 小美女
What's your name, gorgeous?
我叫雷兰
Mine's Raylan.
跟我无关
I don't care.
我得走了 我父亲在等我
I need to go. My father's waiting for me.
只要我打个响指
I snap my fingers
他能把你的蛋蛋给咬下来
and he'll bite your testicles off.
哇
Wow.
好吧
Okay.
如果我吓到你了 我很抱歉
Well, I'm sorry if I scared you.
我才没被你吓到
Who said you did?
回头见
I'll see you around.
来吧 小影
Come on, Shadow.
你还好吗
You okay?
我没事
Yes.
遇到个怪人
Just a weirdo.
嗯
Yeah.
这附近怪人很多
No shortage of those around here.
跟上他们
Follow them.
谢谢 赫尔南德斯
Thanks, Hernandez.
我们今天玩得很开心
We had a lot of fun today.
如果你不介意的话 我下周再带她去
I'll take her again next week if you're okay with it.
不用了
No.
今天玩够了吧
Today was enough.
-虽然这跟我无关 但是 -你说得对
It's none of my business, but--You're right.
本来就跟你无关
It's not.
你觉得你是个坏人
You're a bad man.
做过一些坏事的恶棍
A man who's done terrible things.
我知道你是这么想的
At least, I know you think that.
我有时候也觉得自己很坏
Just like sometimes I do about myself.
战争改变了我们所有人
War changes us all.
战后没有谁的灵魂还是圣洁的
No soul returns holy from it.
但你不应该让她跟你一样承受这些
Don't make her pay for that.
谢谢
Thanks.
你能把你的车子挪开吗
You mind moving your vehicle off the road, please?
这是…
This is...
这是回镇上的唯一一条路
This is the only road back to town.
你当过兵吗
You served?
嗯
Yeah.
我们都当过兵
We all did too.
参加过伊拉克战争吗 -是的
Iraq? Yeah.
从一场不光彩的战争中不光彩地退伍
Dishonorably discharged from a dishonorable war.
但我不知道为什么 我却感觉很光荣 你呢
I'd say that makes us honorable somehow. Wouldn't you?
我不光荣
No.
你现在能把你的车从路上挪开了吗
Can you move your truck off the road now?
当然可以 宝贝
Sure, baby.
你想怎么都可以
Whatever you want.
下个月的课程
Lessons next month.
好的
Okay.
我明年想去上学
I wanna go to school next year.
-在家就能上学 -我想上一所真正的学校
This is school--A real school,
和其他像我一样大的孩子在一起上学
with other kids like me.
在家上学更安全
Homeschool is safer.
我不想要安全
I don't wanna be safe.
我想做个正常人 我想交朋友
I wanna be normal. I wanna have friends.
-我想过一种… -够了
I wanna live a--Enough!
够了
Enough.
我已经失去过一个女儿了
I already lost a daughter once.
我不能再失去你
I'm not losing you.
但是我很孤独
But I'm lonely.
你根本不知道孤独是什么滋味
You have no idea what it is to be alone.
你起码还有我呢
You have me.
有你根本不够
You're not enough.
“圣约人庇护所
"Covenant Shelter.
你的新家正等着你呢”
Your new home awaits you."
小影
Shadow?
Shadow.
天哪
Oh, God.
快拿盒子
The box! Now!
快走
Go!
去抓住那个女孩
Go get the girl.
开门
Open the door.
Open up!
他妈的怎么回事？
What the fuck?
噢！
Oh!
坚持住 兄弟
Hang on, brother.
张嘴
Open your jaw.
忍住
Stay still.
呼吸 兄弟
Breathe, brother.
那家伙是海豹突击队员
The guy's a Navy SEAL.
该死的海豹突击队 兄弟
Fucking dead SEAL, bro.
你最好离开那里 孩子
Better get out of there, kid.
他下来了
He's down there with you!
那该死的瞎子就在下面
Blind fuck is down there!
打电话给雷兰
Call Raylan.
金属盒子里面灌满了水
Metal box is almost full of water.
你要是希望孩子活着…
You prefer to see the kid alive...
就到这里来
you come in here.
你以为我在跟你开玩笑吗
You think I'm fucking with you?
不是的
No.
有一根带电的电线快要通到水里了
There's a live wire about to reach the water.
快出来 不然她就完蛋了
Come out, or she's fried!
真他妈的聪明
Clever fuck.
没枪吧
No guns, huh?
没问题
No problem.
你真是个硬汉
You're tough.
但是你完蛋了
But you're done.
他妈的怎么回事？
What the fuck?
喔  老兄
Yo, bro.
深呼吸
Breathe.
来吧 深呼吸
Come on, breathe.
深呼吸
Breathe.
是那个老瞎子干的吗
The old blind man did this?
嗯 嗯
Uh-huh.
我们走
Let's go.
我可以走
I can walk.
我说了 我可以走
I said, I can walk.
发生什么事了
What's happening?
把守出口
Cover the exits.
他妈的怎么回事？
What the fuck?
他们还在下面
They're still down here.
发生什么事了
What's happening?
他们是谁 -我不知道
Who are they?I don't know.
不要害怕 小姑娘
You don't need to be afraid, little girl.
这一切只是一个误会
This has all just been one big misunderstanding.
你应该害怕的不是我
It's not me you need to be scared of...
而是站在你旁边的那个人
but the man standing next to you.
现在 我不知道他是谁
Now, I don't know who he is.
但我知道他不是什么好人
But I know who he's not.
我应该告诉她还是告诉你
Should I tell her or you?
干掉他 兄弟
Finish him, bro.
不要
No!
-爸爸 爸爸 醒醒 -你不是很厉害吗
Dad! Dad, wake up.Aren't you something?
放开我！
Let me go!
冷静点
Come on.
没事的 没事的
No, it's okay.
好的 就在这样
Yeah, there you go.
这就对了
There you go.
你真的不记得我了 是吗
You really don't remember me, do you?
我就帮你回忆回忆
Maybe this will help.
看见了吗？
See?
什么
What...?
几年前 我们的房子着火了
Years ago, there was a fire in our house.
警察将过错算在了我身上
Cops blamed me.
我在监狱里呆了八年
I spent eight years in prison,
我时刻都想着是否还能再见到你
wondering if I'd ever see you again.
我甚至不知道你是死是活
I didn't even know if you were dead or alive.
这个变态
This creep here must have...
一定是找到了你想把你占为己有
found you and kept you for himself.
接下来是本地新闻
REPORTER Up next in local news,
底特律西部的一家冰毒实验室今早着火
a meth lab caught fire in west Detroit this morning.
警方逮捕了主要嫌疑人
Police were able to arrest the primary suspect.
该男子已被拘留 可能面临指控
The man was taken into custody and could face charges
其身犯数罪
for a large number of crimes committed
-在过去的几年里 -你不知道
over the past several years.You have no idea
我等这一刻有多久了
how much I've been waiting for this moment.
他伤害过你吗
Did he hurt you?
但他确确实实把你从我身边抢走了
But he did steal you away from me,
现在他必须死 你明白吗
and now he must die, you understand?
杀了他
Kill him.
-不 -操 你在干什么
No.Fuck are you doing?
不要在我孩子面前动手 在外面吧
Not in front of my kid. Do it outside.
醒醒 你这个该死的瞎子
Wake up, you blind fuck.
噢！操！
Oh! Fuck!
该死的混蛋
Fucking coward.
把她带到车上 我去追捕这个混蛋
Take her to the truck while I hunt this motherfucker.
我们走吧
Let's go.
-放开我 -你怎么回事
Let me go!What's wrong with you?
不想回家吗
Fucking wanna go home?
我不管你是谁
I don't care who you are.
我要教你一些该死的礼仪 哟
I'm gonna teach you some fucking manners, yo.
你这个忘恩负义的贱人
You ungrateful, little bitch.
不
No.
住手
Stop.
不要
Please!
住手
Stop!
行动 快
Move. Go, go.
Move. Now.
快
Move!
我很抱歉 伙计
I'm sorry, man.
-他回到屋里了 -我知道
He's back in the house.I know.
他想让我们去追他
He wants us to follow him.
这些愚蠢的游戏真是玩够了
Enough of these silly games.
这是他的夹克
JIM- It's his jacket.
好样的
Attaboy.
等等
Wait.
停下
Stop.
是真的吗
Is it true?
快走
Move.
我的真名是什么
What's my real name?
赶紧过来
Get over here now!
我的生日是什么时候
When's my birthday?
-我亲爸是谁 -闭嘴
My real one?Stop it!
你才闭嘴
No, you stop it!
快走
Go!
嘿
Hey.
小凤
Phoenix!
冷静点 丫头
Calm down, girl.
冷静
Calm down.
待着
Stay.
把她带到车上
Put her in the truck.
喔 哇…！
Whoa, whoa, whoa, whoa.
你干嘛呢
What are you doing?
-你的狗在里面  -狗死了
Your dog's in there.Dog's dead.
不一定
You don't know that.
你想去看看吗
You wanna go and find out?
不
No!
早上好 小公主
Good morning, princess.
你感觉怎么样
How you feeling?
你还好吗
You all right?
想和我坐一起吗
Wanna sit with me?
来 坐我旁边来 来吧
Come, sit with me. Come on.
嗯
Yeah.
这就对了
There you go.
嗯
Yeah.
门是开着的
Door's open.
你不再是囚犯了
Not a prisoner anymore.
你是说我可以走了
You mean, I can go?
只要你愿意
If you want.
或者你可以留在这
Or you can stay here
搞清楚你到底是谁
and find out who you really are.
我有兄弟姐妹吗
Do I have any brothers or sisters?
很遗憾 没有
Unfortunately, no.
我的生日是什么时候
When's my birthday?
2月20日
February 20th.
我母亲叫什么名字
What was my mother's name?
约瑟芬
Josephine.
我长得像她吗
Do I look like her?
嗯
Yeah.
你很像她
You do.
塔拉
Tara.
是你的真名
That's your real name.
塔拉
Tara.
那个人告诉你的一切都是谎言
Everything that man told you is a lie.
他怎么样了
What happened to him?
他得到了应有的惩罚
He got what he deserved.
嘿 我不觉得抱歉
Hey. I'm not sorry.
你也不应该害怕
You shouldn't be either.
我想离开
I wanna go.
去哪里？你要去哪里
Where? Where you gonna go?
我知道一个庇护所
There's a shelter I know.
我说了
Like I said,
你不再是囚犯了
you're not a prisoner anymore.
♪ Fly, bird ♪
♪ Out across the ♪
♪ Great wide sea ♪
♪ Sing, girl ♪
♪ Sing your little heart out For me ♪
♪ Fly, bird ♪
♪ Fly across the mighty cliffs ♪
♪ Sleep, girl ♪
妈妈？
Mom?
正如我所说…
Like I said...
他告诉你的一切都是谎言
everything he told you was a lie.
我的小塔拉
My Tara?
你…
You...
长这么大了
got so big, heh.
我可以抱你吗
Can I hug you?
到这儿来
Come here.
哦天哪
Oh, God.
天哪
上帝啊
Mmm. Oh, God.
哦 宝贝 我们太想你了
Oh, baby, we missed you so much.
嗯…
Mmm...
这是你
There you are.
你那时特别乖
You were such a beautiful baby.
拿出来
Get it out.
拿出来 快
Get it out. Come on.
这就对了 这就对了
There you go. There you go. There you go.
-抱歉 -没什么好道歉的
Sorry.Nothing to apologize for.
你没事吧
Are you okay?
就是那场烧毁我们家的大火…
The same fire that destroyed our family...
烧坏了我的内脏
it burned up my insides.
妈妈和爸爸曾经…
Mom and Dad used to have a...
有一个厨房（指制毒室）…
kitchen, heh...
在我们房子的地下室里
in the basement of our house,
我们过去经常在那施展“厨艺”
where we used to cook.
当然那是为了我们的生意
It was for our business.
你渴吗
Are you thirsty?
塔拉
Tara?
我快死了
I'm dying.
什么
What?
那些化学品产生的烟雾…
The smoke from the chemicals...
毒害了我的血液 毒害了我的内脏
poisoned my blood and badly damaged my heart.
我想我时日无多了
I don't think I have much time left.
还有什么别的办法吗
Is there anything you can do?
我听说你在我们的老房子给我种了些花
I heard you left flowers for me at our old house.
是真的吗
Is that true?
噢
Oh.
你是不是希望
Weren't you wishing
妈妈能健康的活着呢
your mama was healthy and alive?
是的
Yes.
我需要一颗新的心脏 宝贝
I need a new heart, baby.
但不是随便什么人的都可以
But not just any heart.
医生说一定得是 呃
Doctor said it has to be a, uh...
那一定得是…
It must be a...
跟我相容的器官捐赠者
compatible donor.
比如 直系亲属
Like a direct relative.
你有着能救妈妈性命的东西
You hold the gift that can save your mama's life.
还有 宝贝 我需要你把它作为礼物送给我
And, baby, I need that gift.
那样我们就可以同呼吸共命运了
We'll finally be together as one.
你会活在我的身体里
You'll live on in me.
回家
Go home.
走开
Go away.
我说了 走
I said, go.
留下来
Stay.
回家
Go home.
我希望你能理解
I hope you understand
这个过程具有着高风险
the high risks of this procedure.
我想我付你的钱够多了
I think I pay you enough.
闭嘴 做好你的工作
Shut up and do your job.
为什么她还活着
Why is she still alive?
如果她死了 她的心脏也废了
If she's dead, so is her heart.
我不能让心脏保鲜足够长的时间
And I can't keep it fresh long enough
我们没有合适的设备
without the proper equipment.
我得趁她还活着的时候把心脏取出来
I have to cut it out of her while she's still breathing.
嘿
JOSEPHINE Hey.
嘿 嘿 嘿
Hey, hey, hey.
嘿 嘿
Hey, hey.
谢谢你
Thank you.
你怎么了 伙计
JIM- What's wrong with you, man?
他们在里面做的那些事是不对的
What they're doing in there is wrong.
她是我们的厨师
She's our cook.
如果她死了 就没人给我们生产毒品了
If she dies, there's no product.
如果没有毒品 我们也活不下去
If there's no product, there's no us.
懂了吗
¿Comprende?
但那样做还是不对的
Still fucking wrong.
嘿
Hey.
准备好了吗 -嗯
You ready? Mm-hm.
我们开始吧
Let's go.
他妈的怎么回事？
What the fuck?
去看看
Go check it out.
嗯
Hm.
你杀了我兄弟
You killed my brother!
你这个死瞎子
You blind freak!
我要像剁南瓜一样剁开你的脑袋
I'm gonna carve your fucking head open like a pumpkin, man.
这是为小影报的仇
This is for Shadow.
哦 他妈的
Oh, fuck.
不
No!
就是他
It's him.
该死 他怎么找到的
How the hell did he find...?
该死的叛徒
Disloyal fucking animal.
一切都还好吗
Is everything okay?
是的 一切无恙
Yeah, everything's okay.
-没事的 我保证 -宝贝 我有点担心
Everything's okay, I promise.Baby, should I be worried?
不 不用担心 完全不用
No, no. Not at all.
有我在呢
I got you. I got you.
没有电 我没办法干活
I can't work without power.
呃…
Uh...
计划有变
Change of plans, then.
收拾好你的东西 带上那女孩
Pack your things. Bring the girl.
劳尔
Raul.
带人过来 杀了那个瞎子
Bring the men. Kill the blind man.
-带多少人 -全带上
How many of us? All of you!
走吧
Let's go.
他们会杀了她的
They're gonna kill her.
我接受不了
And that's not cool with me.
他们现在要走了
They're leaving now.
你身后的梯子
The ladder behind you
直接通往他们那儿
leads directly to them.
你最好快点
You'd better hurry.
左边
Go left.
那边
That way.
他会把你们都杀了
He'll kill you all.
嘿…
Hey, hey! Hey!
早上好 混蛋
Good morning, motherfucker.
-宝贝  -嘘 嘘  没关系的
JOSEPHINE Baby.Shh, shh. It's okay.
停下
Stop it.
宝贝？
Baby?
喂
Hello?
我看不见你
I can't see you.
宝贝？
Baby?
我在这里 你在哪
I'm over here! Where are you?
宝贝？
Baby?
我抓到你了 混蛋
I got you, motherfucker.
不
No.
No! No!
不
No.
No!
小凤
Phoenix!
快…
Now...
你将会看到
you're gonna see
我所看到的
what I see.
小凤
Phoenix?
停下
Stop.
停下来
Oh, stop!
你…
You...
你不要靠近我
You mustn't come near me.
他说的
Everything he said...
都是真的
is true.
我不是你的父亲
I am no father.
我杀过人
I have killed.
我…
I...
还强奸过人
have raped.
我…
I...
我什么都不是
am nothing.
啥也不是…
Nothing...
我是一个怪物
but a monster.
而你…
And you...
不能在我身边
cannot be around me.
不能
Ever.
你走吧
So go.
走吧
Now. Go.
走啊
Go!
天哪
Oh, God.
塔拉
Tara?
不
No.
No. No.
不要
Please.
No, no, no.
我来帮你吧
Let me help you.
我可以救你
I can save you.
你已经救了我了
You already have.
嘿
Hey.
你们这儿还能多容纳一个人吗
Think there's room for one more?
我相信可以的的
I'm sure there is.
你叫什么名字
What's your name?
我叫小凤
My name is Phoenix.